(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
USADA PEKORA
周年3D LIVE ぺこらRUSH！！
Anniversary 3D LIVE Pekora RUSH!!
君に逢いたい時だって
Even when I want to see you
どこか逢えない気持ちがある
There's a feeling I can't meet you somewhere
だけど本当の優しさが
But true kindness
そこにあるかも知れない
Might be right there
そこにあるかも知れない…
～Special Full Version～
Maybe It's There...
~Special Full Version~
人込みに揺られてる
Swayed by the crowd
どこかに宛てがあるわけじゃない
It's not like I have a destination
独りきり歩いても
Even if I walk alone
何か解決することじゃない
It's not something that will solve anything
自分が本当に望んでる
What I truly desire
気持ちはきっと
This feeling, for sure
これから二人で歩いて行くことさ
Is to walk together from now on
※この配信は演出により激しく点滅する場面がございます
部屋を明るくし画面から十分離れてご視聴ください
Intense flashing lights. Watch in a bright room
and stay a safe distance from the screen.
君に逢いたい時だって
Even when I want to see you
どこか逢えない気持ちがある
There's a feeling I can't meet you somewhere
だけど本当の優しさが
But true kindness
そこにあるかも知れない
Might be right there
二人輝いた季節は
The season when we two sparkled
きっとこれからも続いていく
Will surely continue from now on
だから大切な未来に
So, to the precious future
この想いを残したい
I want to leave these feelings behind
飽きるまで話しても
Even if we talk until we're tired
全部分かり合えるわけじゃない
We won't understand everything
言葉より伝えたい
More than words, I want to convey
気持ちがこの胸に溢れてる
The feelings overflowing in my heart
君がいつか探した夢の
Of the dream you once searched for
続きはきっと二人で描いて行こう
Let's draw the continuation together
忘れないで
Don't forget
独りきり孤独なようで
As if being all alone and lonely
皆何かに悩んでいる
Everyone is worrying about something
すぐには変わらないけれど
Though it won't change immediately
とにかく信じていたい
Anyway, I want to believe
流した涙捨て去って
Throwing away the tears I've shed
ずっと君のそばで生きたい
I want to live by your side forever
いつか振り返った時に
When I look back someday
後悔したくないから
Because I don't want to regret it
キミに...
To you...
会いたいと言いたくて
I want to say I want to see you
ふたり...
The two of us...
輝いた季節は
The season we shined
後悔したくないから
Because I don't want to regret
叶わない 夢なんて
Dreams that won't come true
簡単に 口にはしたくない
I don't want to easily say them
諦めた 瞬間に
At the moment you give up
自分自身 終わらせてるだけ
You're just ending it yourself
もっと 単純に感じたい
I want to feel more simply
君のこと いつも
About you, always
素直に 笑うよ
I'll smile honestly
未来は 続いていく
The future continues
君が ホントにスキだーって
That I really like you
いつも 心に飾ってたい
I always want to keep it in my heart
楽しさだけが 全てなら
If fun is everything
本当の 愛じゃないから
It's not real love
キミに...
To you...
会いたいと言いたくて
I want to say I want to see you
二人 輝いた季節は
The season the two of us shined
きっと これからも続いていく
will surely continue from now on
だから 大切な未来に
So, to the precious future
この想いを 残したい
I want to leave these feelings
キミに...
To you...
会いたいと言いたくて
I want to say I want to see you
二人...
The two of us...
輝いた季節は...
The season we shined...
みんな！6周年ライブに来てくれてありぺこー！
Everyone! Thanks for coming to the 6th anniversary live!
そして大変お待たせいたしました！
And thank you very much for waiting!
すいません、すいません、けどね！
Sorry, sorry, but!
みんなに楽しんでもらえるようなライブになってるぺこだから、是非ともお楽しみに！
It's a live that everyone can enjoy, so please look forward to it!
そして1曲目は「そこに、あるかもしれない」を歌わせてもらったぺこ！
And the first song I sang was 'Soko ni, Aru kamo Shirenai'!
ま、っていうことは今回のテーマは...
Well, that means this time's theme is...
パチスロ第2弾！イエーイ！
Pachi-slot 2nd series! Yay!
当たり演出もね、めちゃめちゃいろいろありますんで、
There are many winning effects too,
是非とも次の曲は何来るかなーって考えながら楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいぺこ！
so I'd be happy if you enjoyed it while thinking 'what song will come next'!
そして今回のハッシュタグはこちら！
And here's this time's hashtag!
兎田ぺこら6周年記念ライブぺこなので、たくさんポストしてください！
It's Usada Pekora 6th Anniversary Live, so please post a lot!
というわけで、そんじゃ早速回していくか！
Anyway, let's start spinning it!
よいしょ、あれ？
Heave-ho, huh?
お？始まった！
Oh? It started!
運命の一撃
Blow of Fate
笑うべきだと分かった時は泣くべきじゃねえぺこ！
When you know you should laugh, you shouldn't cry!
運命の一撃を叩き込め！
Drive in the blow of fate!
咲かすか　枯らすか　現在
Bloom or wither, right now
燃えるように　陽が沈む
The sun sets, as if burning
歯車が回る
The gears are turning
ラッパが鳴れば　千客万来
When the trumpet sounds, guests flock in
また楽しの物語
Another fun story
はしゃがらばら　たっしゃがらがら
Frolicking and clattering about
真っ赤な過去が追いかける
A deep red past is chasing me
道化師の笑み　仮面の裏側
The clown's smile, behind the mask
溶かしても消えない　傷が痛んでも
Even if wounds that won't melt away hurt
咲かすか　枯らすか　現在
Bloom or wither, right now
燃えるように　陽が沈む
The sun sets, as if burning
真夜中の暗い孤独から
From the dark loneliness of midnight
繰り出す
I set forth
微かに響く鐘が
The faintly echoing bell
陰る日々の道しるべ
Is the guide through darkened days
音の鳴る先へ
Toward the source of the sound
ラッパが鳴れば　千客万来
When the trumpet sounds, guests flock in
また楽しの演目の数
Yet more fun performances
幕間の間　まだまだか
Is the intermission over yet?
真っ逆さま　躓くのに
Falling headlong, though I stumble
足を掴まれ　奈落の底まで
Dragged by my feet to the bottom of the abyss
明日さえも忘れて　息もできない
Forgetting even tomorrow, I can't even breathe
咲かすか　枯らすか　現在
Bloom or wither, right now
眠るように　目を閉じる
I close my eyes as if falling asleep
身体中　巡る猛毒から
From the deadly poison coursing through me
逃げ出す
I escape
微かに響く鐘に
Toward the faintly echoing bell
耳を澄ませ　生きるのか
Listen closely, will I survive?
どちらか選べ
Choose one
さぁ
Come now
回顧　爪のように
Retrospection, like claws
未来だけ想えばいい
I only need to think of the future
覚悟も　ほら　焼き捨てた
See, I've burned away even my resolution
咲かすか　枯らすか　現在
Bloom or wither, right now
燃えるように　陽が沈む
The sun sets, as if burning
真夜中の深い孤独から
From the deep loneliness of midnight
繰り出す
I set forth
運命が壊れるような
With a voice as if
声で叫べ
Destiny is breaking, scream out
始まりの合図　幕開け様々
The signal to begin, various curtains rise
踊るさ
I'll dance
最後には涙流す
Tears will flow in the end
だから今は堪え進む
So for now, I'll endure and move on
幕が降りるその時まで
Until the moment the curtain falls
まだ
Still
絶えず　歯車が回る
The gears turn without ceasing
究極Vモンキー！
Ultimate V-Monkey!
ココロが止まらない
My heart won't stop
何かをするのに
When doing something
理由なんかいらないね
A reason isn't necessary, right?
近づけるよ
We can get closer.
君を見ているだけで
Just by looking at you,
戦っているのよ
I'm fighting.
期待はどんな時でも
Expectations, at any time,
もつれて迷い込む
Become tangled and lost.
イチかバチか夢に向かい加速する
Taking a chance, accelerating towards the dream.
ココロが止まらない 感じてる
My heart won't stop, I'm feeling it.
悩み多き日常のターンに
In the turn of a worry-filled daily life,
君といる時の自分が一番好きだよ
I like myself best when I'm with you.
ココロは止まらない 光の中
My heart won't stop, in the middle of the light.
七色の水しぶきあげて
Kicking up rainbow-colored water sprays,
新しい明日の風に向かい走り出そうよ
Let's start running towards the wind of a new tomorrow.
二人きりで
Just the two of us.
会いたい気持ちが
The feeling of wanting to see you
ため息に溶けてゆく
Dissolves into a sigh.
寂しいよ
It's lonely.
すぐそばにいてくれた
You were right by my side,
泣き出しそうになった時
When I felt like I was about to burst into tears.
気づかないふりしてくれたね
You pretended not to notice, didn't you?
重ねる唇から
From our overlapping lips,
こぼれる切なさも愛しさも
Both sadness and love overflow.
ココロが止まらない 感じてる
My heart won't stop, I'm feeling it.
もっとすべてを叶えてみたい
I want to try to make everything come true.
願った奇跡がこんなにも近くにあったよ
The miracle I wished for was so close all along.
ココロは止まらない 通り過ぎた
My heart won't stop, the scent of summer
夏の匂い懐かしいね
Passing by is so nostalgic.
君を好きになってから前より寂しがり屋に
Since I fell in love with you, I've become lonelier than before.
なってしまった
That's what happened.
こわいものはたったひとつ
There's only one thing I'm afraid of.
君が優しすぎること
It's that you're too kind.
例えそれが風のいたずらでも
Even if it's just a trick of the wind,
夢へのブレーキがかからない
There's no brake on this dream.
ココロが止まらない 感じてる
My heart won't stop, I'm feeling it.
きっと答えはひとつじゃない
I'm sure there's not just one answer.
君に会うためだけにとても優しくなれるよ
Just to meet you, I can become very kind.
ココロは止まらない 月の雫
My heart won't stop, the moon's droplets,
ずっと君を探してた
I was searching for you all along.
同じ時 同じ星 見上げて このままずっと
Looking up at the same star, at the same time, forever like this,
色あせぬように
So that it never fades.
リーチ
Reach!
輝くマリンブルー
Shining Marine Blue.
やっと出会ったサマータイム
Finally encountered summertime.
ミラクルマリンパワー
Miracle Marine Power.
せーので飛び込もう！
Let's jump in together!
Go! Go!
Let's Go!
SEA STORY
海物語 〜Go! Go! SEA STORY セカンドシーズン〜
Sea Story ~Go! Go! SEA STORY Second Season~
太陽サンサン裸足で
Sun shining bright, barefoot
駆け出して行こうビーチへ
Let's run out to the beach
ココナッツ 冒険
Coconut adventure
見つけに行こう海の中のワンダーランド
Let's go find the wonderland in the sea
みんな歌えば
If everyone sings
イルカ達もジャンプ
The dolphins jump too
カニとタコのダンス
Crab and octopus dance
スペシャルな夢を描こう
Let's draw a special dream
輝くマリンブルー
Shining marine blue
やっと出会えたサマータイム
Finally met, summertime
ミラクルマリンパワー
Miracle marine power
せーの！で飛び込もう
On three! Let's dive in
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY
海底探検泳いで
Swimming on an undersea exploration
一緒に遊びに行こうよ
Let's go play together
笑顔が何よりの
A smile is more than anything
たったひとつの宝物だよ
The only treasure there is
シャチの背中に
On the back of an orca
サンゴのトンネル
Coral tunnel
クラゲのリズム
Jellyfish rhythm
始まる夢のステージ
The dream stage begins
きらめくマリンスノー
Sparkling marine snow
みんな一緒にEveryday
Everyone together Everyday
スペシャルサマーゾーン
Special Summer Zone
せーの！で始めよう
On three! Let's begin
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY
輝くマリンブルー
Shining marine blue
やっと出会えたサマータイム
Finally met, summertime
ミラクルマリンパワー
Miracle marine power
せーの！で飛び込もう
On three! Let's dive in
グレートマリンブルー
Great marine blue
水平線の彼方まで
To the other side of the horizon
ミラクルマリンパワー
Miracle marine power
せーの！で飛び込もう
On three! Let's dive in
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY
ルパン三世のテーマ
Theme from Lupin III
BIG CHANCE
ルパン三世のテーマ
Theme from Lupin III
真赤な薔薇は あいつの唇
The bright red roses are her lips
やさしく抱きしめて くれとねだる
Begging to be held gently
瞳の奥に 獲物を映して
Reflecting the prey in the depths of those eyes
寂しく問いかける 愛の在りか
Sadly asking where love can be found
男には 自分の世界がある
A man has his own world
たとえるなら 空をかける 一筋の流れ星
To use a metaphor, a single shooting star streaking across the sky
孤独な笑みを 夕陽にさらして
Exposing a lonely smile to the setting sun
背中で泣いてる 男の美学
A man's aesthetics, weeping in the shadows
真珠の色は あいつのまなざし
The color of pearls is in his gaze
遥かな幸せを 夢に描く
Painting dreams of a far-off happiness
いためることを 恐れるあまりに
For fear of causing pain
冷たく突き放す 愛もあるさ
There is a love that coldly pushes away
男には 自分の世界がある
A man has his own world
たとえるなら 風をはらい 荒れ狂う稲光
If I were to compare it, it's like brushing away the wind, a raging bolt of lightning
都会の闇に 体を溶かして
Melting into the city's darkness
口笛吹いてる 男の美学
Whistling as he goes, a man's aesthetics
Amazing Grace, how sweet the sound
That saved a wretch like me...
$15 GET
ムコアタック 突入！
Entering Miko Attack!
いざ勝負！
Let's battle!
勝負ぺこ！
It's a showdown, peko!
いざ勝負！
Let's battle!
勝利
Victory
楽勝ぺこ！
Easy win, peko!
夜を彷徨う影が 光探そうと吠える
The shadows wandering the night howl, searching for light
罪深き羊たち 来なさい容赦はしません
Sinful sheep, come forth; I will show no mercy.
守るべき人のため 優しい心のため
For the sake of the people I must protect, for the sake of a kind heart
どんなに傷つこうと 祈りましょう
No matter how much I get hurt, let's pray.
御意に誓う命かけて 救援を戦場、駆けて
With lives pledged to the will, rushing to the battlefield for rescue.
信じた仲間たちと この手に宿る力信じて
With the friends I believe in, believing in the power that resides in this hand.
狂い咲けよ 闘志の華よ
Bloom wildly, flower of fighting spirit
戦の地に降り立つ夢
A dream descending on the land of battle
大輪の炎 闇を撃ち散らして
A great bloom of flame, scattering the darkness
勝利を 勇気と熱を楯に
Victory, with courage and passion as your shield
掴め 辿り着く金色の空
Grasp it, the golden sky you finally reach
笑顔を育む大地へ
To the land that nurtures smiles
夜はいずれ去り 朝が訪れる
The night will eventually pass, and morning will arrive
全てを越えて 君の愛 叶う
Overcoming everything, your love will come true
星の巡りを辿り 手にした希望の十字
Tracing the movement of stars, the cross of hope held in hand
後悔などしないわ 赦しは私が与える
I will have no regrets, I am the one who grants forgiveness
発射仕掛けの恋 光が導きし舞
A love of widespread artifice, a dance guided by light
大胆不敵な場所 奇跡生まれる楽園
A fearless place, a paradise where miracles are born
さあ 共に往きましょう
Come, let us go together
正義は必ず勝つ いつでも
Justice will always prevail, forever
空を渡る 溢れだし燃える想いが
Crossing the sky, overflowing and burning feelings
鮮やかに彩る虹へ 瞳を交わして絆を
Towards a vividly colored rainbow, exchanging glances and bonds
結べば 見えてくる新しい朝が
If tied, a new morning will come into view
胸の中を 雨はやがて止み 癒すよ
Inside the heart, the rain will eventually stop and heal you
過去を解き放ち 君の夢を問う
Release the past, and ask of your dream
貴方と想いを 数えきれないほどの出会いと別れ 重ねて
With you and my feelings, countless encounters and partings piling up
真実 人は生きる意味を見つける
The truth, people find the meaning of life
狂い咲けよ 闘志の華よ
Bloom wildly, flower of fighting spirit
戦の地に降り立つ夢
A dream descending on the land of battle
大輪の炎 闇を撃ち散らして
A great bloom of flame, scattering the darkness
勝利を 勇気と熱を楯に
Victory, with courage and passion as your shield
辿り着く金色の空
The golden sky you finally reach
笑顔を育む大地へ
To the land that nurtures smiles
祝福が 朝は訪れる
A blessing, morning will arrive
全てを越えて 君の愛 叶う
Overcoming everything, your love will come true
待っていたぞ、ぺこら。
I have been waiting for you, Pekora.
出てこい！
Come out!
ゲットー！
Got it!
Welcome to this crazy Time
このイカれた時代へようこそ君は
Welcome to this crazy era, you are
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
まともな奴ほど feel so bad
The more sane you are, the more you feel so bad
正気でいられるなんて運がイイぜ you
You're lucky to be able to stay sane
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
時はまさに世紀末
The time is exactly the end of the century
淀んだ街角で僕らは出会った
We met at a stagnant street corner
Keep you burning 駆け抜けて
Keep you burning, run through
この腐敗と自由と暴力のまっただなか
In the midst of this decay, freedom, and violence
No boy no cry 悲しみは
No boy no cry, sadness is
絶望じゃなくて明日のマニフェスト
Not despair, but the manifesto of tomorrow
We are living, living in the eighties
We still fight, fighting in the eighties
どこもかしこも傷だらけ
Everywhere is covered in wounds
うずくまって泣いていてもはじまらないから
Because crouching and crying won't start anything
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
どっちを向いても feel so sad
No matter which way I look, I feel so sad
だけど死には至らない気分はどうだい？
But it's not fatal; how do you feel?
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
ここは永遠のロックランド
This is the eternal Rockland
拳を握りしめ僕らは出会った
We met with clenched fists
Keep you burning 駆け抜けて
Keep you burning, run through it
この狂気と希望と幻滅のまっただなか
Right in the midst of this madness, hope, and disillusionment
No boy no cry 進まなきゃ
No boy no cry, I must keep moving forward
勢いを増した向い風の中を
Through the headwind that has increased in strength
We are living, living in the eighties
We still fight, fighting in the eighties
We still fight, fighting in the eighties...
We are living, living in the eighties
We still fight, fighting in the eighties
野うさぎ討伐戦 突入！
Nousagi Subjugation Battle: Commencing!
1体目！
1st target!
お前の英雄は超うさぎが勝ってるぺこ！
Your hero is being outplayed by Super Rabbit-peko!
PUSHぺこ！
PUSH peko!
ごちそうさまでした！
Thanks for the meal!
完全撃破！
Complete annihilation!
This is the fate that brought us here, watch my Long shot
Feel like I have falling into the flame of lies
Tell me what you want from me
Try not to step back to where I used to belong
Looking for the escape from pain
I will cross my fingers hoping not to be sacrificed
理想像なんてどっか葬り
Burying the ideal image somewhere
Get in the way, get ready for the time to come
浮かび上がるシルエット追いかけ
Chasing the silhouette that emerges
Tell me the reason why I'm standing here alone
Maybe it's already too late to regain
思い描いてた面影を失くさないで
Don't lose the visage you envisioned
I count my wrongs and save you from the pain
It's not enough, it's not enough for me to break the rule upon this world
I will never gonna leave you, never wanna lose you
We'll make it in the end
Not backing down for real
I won't trace someone else's life
I know who I am
Blame me if I messed up anything
Take the risk of everything
Justify this cruel world
金持ちにして 叫び声
Make me rich, the sound of screams
吸い込まれてく 賭け事通して
Being sucked in through gambling
I will cross my fingers
Hoping not to be sacrificed
一掃して 研ぎ澄ますのさ 万全に
Wipe them out and sharpen it perfectly
Get involved, get ready for the time to come
浮かび上がる シルエットを 追いかけ
Chasing the silhouette that emerges
And don't be afraid of yourself, it's over
何度だっていいんだ
It doesn't matter how many times
覚悟してんだ
I'm prepared for it
全て
Everything
守ると決めたよ
I've decided to protect
君がいるから
Because you are here
絡み合う未来を
The intertwined future
この手で変えてみせると
I'll show you I can change it with these hands
すべきことは
What I must do
分かっているから
Because I know
Take this pain away from me
この胸の鼓動にのせて
Riding on the heartbeat in this chest
There's no way I can feel
届けて 欲しかった 願いは...
The wish I wanted to be delivered...
Put down the reason why I'm standing near alone
Maybe it's already too late to regain
運命として掲げた日を なくさないで
Don't lose the day we held up as destiny
Brace yourself, don't forget this is your fate
What if I could write my wrongs and save you from the pain
It's not enough, it's not enough for me to break
The rule of all this world
I will never gonna leave you
Never wanna lose you
I'll make it in the end
Not backing down for real
I won't chase someone else's life
I know who I am
待っていたのはこの瞬間
This is the moment I've been waiting for
ボーナス確定ぺこ！
Bonus confirmed-peko!
聞こえますか
Can you hear it?
かなで広がる夢に
In the dream that expands with the melody
手を解き放て
Release your hands
聞こえますか
Can you hear it?
いのちはじまる鼓動
The heartbeat where life begins
愛を突き上げて
Raise up your love
遥か彼方 星は音楽となったあの日
Far away, on that day the stars became music
風は凪いで 笑いやがて 伝え紡ぐ鼓動を
The wind calmed, and laughter soon followed, the heartbeat conveyed and woven together
歌にした そして 夢は開くよ 見たことない世界の果てへ
Turned into a song, and then the dream will open, to the ends of a world never seen before
Yes, just believe
神様も知らない
Not even God knows
ヒカリで歴史を創ろう
Let's create history with light
不死なる焔 未来照らす
The immortal flame illuminates the future
一緒に飛ばないか？
Shall we fly together?
Just Believe 涙で濡れたハネ
Just Believe, wings wet with tears
重くて羽ばたけない日は WISH
On days too heavy to flap, WISH
その右手に添えよう
Let's place it in that right hand
描くチカラを
The power to draw
鳥のように はためき合うよ Singing Heart
Like a bird, we'll flutter together, Singing Heart
いつの日にか わかる時が来るから
Because one day, the time to understand will come
ずっと忘れない
I'll never forget
その時には 心のアルカディアに
At that time, in the Arcadia of your heart
笑顔忘れない
Don't forget the smiles
言葉なんていらない
Words are not needed
未知の地平の先
Beyond the unknown horizon
強く 満ちて 繋ぎ 合う
Strongly, fully, connecting
ハーモニー舞う 七色の翼
Harmony dancing, rainbow-colored wings
そして生きる 今を
And live the now
見たことない明日の先へ
Beyond the tomorrow never seen before
Yes Just Believe 千年後の今日も
Yes Just Believe, a thousand years from now
生まれ変わって 歌いたい
I want to be reborn and sing
暖かいよ この温もり
It's warm, this warmth
絶対 離さない
I'll never let go
Just Believe 運命なんてない
Just Believe, there's no such thing as fate
物語は 自分にある Jump
The story is within yourself, Jump
逃げ出したくなったら
When you feel like running away
宇宙を見上げよう
Let's look up at the universe
勇気こそが 輝くんだよ Singing Star
Courage is what shines, Singing Star
遥か 星が 音楽となったあの日
That day far away when the stars became music
多分 共に 出会い 響き
Probably together, meeting, resonating
神話の一つとなるように
To become part of a myth
紡いだ 何も 怖くないよ
Spun together, nothing to be afraid of
見たことない世界の果てへ
To the end of the world never seen before
Yes Just Believe
神様も知らない
Even God doesn't know
ヒカリで 歴史を作ろう
Let's make history with light
不死なるほど 未来照らす
Illuminating the future enough to be immortal
一緒に飛ばないか？
Shall we fly together?
Just Believe 涙で濡れたハネ
Just Believe, wings wet with tears
重くて羽ばたけない日は WISH
On days too heavy to flap, WISH
旋律は 溶け合って
The melodies melt together
シンフォニーへと
Into a symphony
鳥のように はためき合うよ Singing Heart
Like a bird, we'll flutter together, Singing Heart
虹は架かる すべては夢と共に
A rainbow will form, all together with dreams
野うさぎ剣を押し込め
Push in the Nousagi Sword
行け 疾風のごとく
Go, like a gale
宿命の剣士よ
O knight of fate
闇に紛れて
Mixing with the darkness
何故闘うのか
Why do you fight?
...のだろうか それは剣に聞け
...I wonder? Ask the sword.
正義だとか愛など 俺は追いかけない
Justice or love—I don't chase after such things.
闇に生まれ闇に忍び 闇を切り裂く
Born in darkness, hiding in darkness, I tear the darkness apart.
遥かな いにしえから受け継いだ
Inherited from the distant, ancient past...
使命だから
...because it's my mission!
行け！ 疾風のごとく 魔戒の剣士よ
Go! Like a gale, O Makai Knight!
月満つる夜に
On this night of the full moon,
金色になれ
turn into gold!
雄々しき姿の 孤独な戦士よ
A lonely warrior with a valiant figure,
魂を込めた 怒りの刃叩きつけて
Strike down with your blade of wrath, imbued with your soul!
時代に輝け 牙狼！
Shine through the ages, GARO!
いつの日かお前に 分かって欲しい
I want you to understand someday,
戦いだけに生きた俺の胸の内を
what's inside the heart of one who lived only for battle.
愛に逸れ 愛に憎み 愛を求める
Straying from love, hating love, seeking love.
わずかな 安らぎさえ打ち捨てた
Casting aside even the slightest peace...
誓いだけど
...it's my vow!
立て！ 修羅のごとく 魔戒の剣士よ
Stand! Like an Asura, O Makai Knight!
運命の歌の 命ずるままに
Just as the song of destiny commands!
月夜に輝く 孤高の戦士よ
A solitary warrior shining in the moonlight,
迫り来る影を 一網打尽 叩き斬って
Strike and cut down the approaching shadows all at once!
気高く吠えろ 牙狼！
Howl noble and high, GARO!
行け！ 疾風のごとく 魔戒の剣士よ
Go! Like a gale, O Makai Knight!
月満つる夜に
On this night of the full moon,
金色になれ
turn into gold!
雄々しき姿の 孤独な戦士よ
A lonely warrior with a valiant figure,
魂を込めた 怒りの刃叩きつけて
Strike down with your blade of wrath, imbued with your soul!
時代に輝け 牙狼！
Shine through the ages, GARO!
行け！ 疾風のごとく 定めの剣士よ
Go! Like a gale, O Knight of Destiny!
闇に光を
Bring light to the darkness!
警戒
Caution
ボーナス、確定
Bonus Confirmed
今度こそ君だけは幸せにしてみせるぺこ
This time, I'll definitely make only you happy, peko.
ボーナス確定
Bonus Confirmed
これが実力ぺこ
This is my true power, peko.
悲しい日々が化石に変わるよ もうすぐ
Sad days will turn into fossils soon.
あなたのその痛みを 眠りの森へと ひそやかに導いてあげる
I'll quietly guide your pain to the forest of sleep.
おやすみ すべてに 一途すぎた迷い子たち
Goodnight to all you stray children who were too earnest.
はがゆい 夢に 進化する日まで
Until the day you evolve into an impatient dream.
生命はまぶしい 朝を待っている 最後の懺悔もかなわないなら
Life is waiting for a bright morning, if even your last confession won't be granted.
いつか時代の夜が明ける 世界よまぶたを閉じて
One day, the dawn of a new era will come. Oh world, close your eyelids.
生命は目覚めて 時を紡ぎだす あなたの証拠をさかのぼるように
Life awakens and begins to spin time, as if tracing back the evidence of your existence.
そして光が胸に届く 心よ原始に戻れ
And then, the light reaches your heart. Heart, return to your origins.
涙の岸で ずっとたたずんだ
Standing still for a long time on the shore of tears.
気持ちを やさしく包むように 秘密の薬が 思い出の沖へと 運ぶよ
As if gently wrapping your feelings, a secret medicine carries them out to the sea of memories.
おやすみ 毛布に 汚れていた指も耳も
Goodnight to the blanket, to your dirty fingers and ears.
この腕の中で もう眠りなさい
Now, sleep within these arms.
生命はまぶしい 朝を待っている 破れた聖書を抱きしめるより
Life is waiting for a bright morning, rather than clinging to a torn Bible.
いつか時代の夜が明ける あなたよ祈りを捨てて
One day, the dawn of a new era will come. You, cast aside your prayers.
生命は目覚めて 時を紡ぎだす 自然の法則にその身をまかせ
Life awakens and begins to spin time, entrusting oneself to the laws of nature.
そして光が胸に届く 心よ原始に戻れ
And then, the light reaches your heart. Heart, return to your origins.
生命はまぶしい 朝を待っている 最後の懺悔もかなわないなら
Life is waiting for a bright morning, if even your last confession won't be granted.
いつか時代の夜が明ける 世界よまぶたを閉じて
One day, the dawn of a new era will come. Oh world, close your eyelids.
生命は目覚めて 時を紡ぎだす あなたの証拠をさかのぼるように
Life awakens and begins to spin time, as if tracing back the evidence of your existence.
そして光が胸に届く 心よ原始に戻れ
And then, the light reaches your heart. Heart, return to your origins.
ノエル？ フレア？
Noel? Flare?
マリン、みんな、どこ行っちゃったぺこなの？
Marine, everyone, where did you all go-peko?
まいっか、三期生ならなんとかなるよな、きっと。
Oh well, since it's the 3rd Gen, it'll work out somehow, surely.
ということで、ここまでたくさんのゲストのみんなと、
And so, having sung many songs with many guests so far...
たくさんの曲を歌ってきましたが、みんな、よ...
...did everyone enj...
ホップ、ステップ、温まりましたかー？
Hop, step, are you all warmed up?
楽しんでくれていますかー？
Are you having a good time?
最後にもね、一曲ぺこらまた歌いますので、そちらもお楽しみにということで、
I'll be singing one more song at the end, so look forward to that!
ここからは、グッズ紹介！
And now, it's time for the goods intro!
お、あれ？
Oh, what's this?
お、ペコった！
Oh, it's Peko-ing!
お、なんだ？
Oh, what is it?
行っけー、ぺこラッシュ！
Go, Peko-Rush!
ということで、兎田ぺこら活動6周年記念グッズを紹介するぺこー！
So, I'm going to introduce my 6th-anniversary commemorative goods-peko!
まずは1つ目はこちら！
First off, here's the first one!
ぺこら推し法被！
The Pekora-Oshi Happi coat!
こちらは悠木はぐれ先生に書いていただきました。
This was illustrated by Hagure Yuki-sensei.
もうね、着るだけで推しをアピールできる。イベントでも着てきてほしいぺこです。
You can show off your support just by wearing it. I want you to wear it to events-peko.
めちゃめちゃ可愛い法被ぺこなんで、是非ともよろ！
It's a super cute happi coat, so please check it out!
そして2つ目はこちら！
And the second one is this!
ラバーマット！
A rubber mat!
な、な、なんとついにぺこらマミィも映っているグッズが出てしまいました。
Wh-wh-what?! Finally, merchandise featuring Pekora Mommy is here.
こちらラバーマットです。イラストはひこさんにお願いしております。
This is the rubber mat. The illustration is by Hikosam-san.
テーマはカジノの兎田ぺこらとぺこらマミィです。ついに出てしまった、マミィが。
The theme is Usada Pekora and Pekora Mommy at a casino. Mommy is finally on merchandise!
だからね、是非ともぺこらマミィ大好きな人も、お手に取ってもらえると嬉しいぺこです。
So, I'd be happy if those who love Pekora Mommy also got their hands on this-peko.
そしてラバーマットがあるということは、3つ目はこちら！
And if there's a rubber mat, that means the third one is...
はい、カードスリーブもちゃんとあるぺこです！
Yes, card sleeves! We have those too-peko!
60枚入りでね、イラストは先ほどと同じひこさんにお願いしております。
It's a pack of 60, and the illustration is by Hikosam-san again.
なんとこちら、ホロカでも使えますので、
And these can actually be used for Hololive Official Card Game!
是非ともホロカで遊んでる方は、使っていただけると嬉しいぺこです。
So for those of you playing Holo-ca, I'd be happy if you used them-peko.
そして4つ目はこちら！
And the fourth one is this!
可愛いね！ぺこーらぬいぐるみキーホルダー！
It's so cute! The Peko-ra plushie keychain!
カバンに付けてもよし、旅行先に持って行くのもよしの、
Great for your bag or taking on trips,
持ち運びやすいサイズのぬいぐるみとなってるぺこ。
it's the perfect portable size for a plushie-peko.
こちら、なんとフルセット購入の特典がございます！
And we have a bonus for those who buy the full set!
数量限定で、直筆サイン入りポストカードがあります！
There's a limited number of postcards with real autographs!
そしてね、通常バージョンは、箔押し複製サイン入りのポストカードとなってまして、
The standard version has a foil-stamped printed autograph,
はぐれ先生のハピのイラストとなっております。
featuring Hagure-sensei's happi illustration.
是非ともジャンジャンバリバリ買ってぺこー！
Please buy lots and lots of them-peko!
それでは、最後は何の曲かなー？
Now then, what will the final song be?
お楽しみに！
Look forward to it!
お、あれ？
Oh, what?
係員をお呼びください
Please call a staff member.
ちょっと、変！ライブできない、ライブできない！直してちょうだい！
Wait, something's wrong! I can't do the live! Fix it, please!
おい、監視カメラ見えてんだろ！おい、どこだ、どこだ！
Hey, you're watching on the camera, right?! Where are you?!
直して早く！ライブできないぺこだよ！
Fix it quick! I can't do the live-peko!
叩いててもダメぺこでしょ！
Hitting it won't help-peko!
叩いても蹴っても直らないだろ！ちょっと！
Hitting or kicking it won't fix it! Come on!
仮想の世に生まれ 生きること
Born into a virtual world, to live...
即ち 戦い、勝つこと
Namely, to fight and to win.
時代と戦い 己が宿命と戦い 己自身に打ち勝つ
Fighting the era, fighting fate, and overcoming oneself.
いつの世も大差はなし
It's the same in any age.
人の生き様が 一瞬の煌めきが 歴史を紡いでいく
The way people live, the flash of a moment, spins history.
今こそ胸に刻め 我が生き様を！
Now, carve it into your heart! My way of life!
永久に語り継げ 兎田の魂を
Hand down forever, the soul of Usada!
戦の炎 灯してみせよう！
Let me light the flames of battle!
Are you ready?
Shall We Dance? 始めよう
Shall We Dance? Let's begin
勝利の祝杯あげる前に
Before we raise the victory toast
Relax Your Body 深呼吸
Relax Your Body, take a deep breath
そうすりゃだんだん高まる Passion, Force
Then the Passion and Force will gradually rise
Passion Force
Y.U.K.I.M.U.R.A
腰をもっと引き上げたら右手上げ Yeah!
Lift your hips more and raise your right hand, yeah!
まるまるまるまるまる六文銭
Round and round, the six coins crest.
まだまだいけるはずだもっともっともっともっともっと!
You can still go further, more, more, more, more, more!
Take a Chance! Take a Chance!
勝利のために
For the victory!
Take a Chance! Take a Chance!
Well Done!
SANADA DA DANCE SANADA DA DANCE
日の本一のつわもの
The greatest warrior in all of Japan.
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA CHA RA CHA CHA CHA
不惜身命だぜ
To risk one's life.
SANADA DA DANCE SANADA DA DANCE
急げ夜が明ける前に
Hurry, before the night breaks.
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA CHA RA CHA CHA CHANCE
熱く熱く火照ったなら
If you're feeling hot and fired up.
踊れ歌え! SANADANCE EXERCISE
Dance and sing! SANADANCE EXERCISE
Wow Wow Wow...
(It's Cypher time)
Close your eyes 瞑想
Close your eyes, meditation.
Don't think, Feel 感覚 研ぎ澄ませたなら高まる
Don't think, feel. If you sharpen your senses...
Passion Force
...the Passion Force will rise.
Y.U.K.I.M.U.R.A
フロントキックでツイストかまして視線は下げずにハイ、ポーズ!
Throw a front kick with a twist, keep your eyes up and say, "Pose!"
回って回ってブンブン回って回転スピードマシマシ!
Spin and spin, spin around and round, increase the rotation speed!
息ついてそうさ もっともっともっともっと!
Catch your breath, that's it, more, more, more, more!
Change the world! Change the world!
Do or Do not
There is no try
SANADA DA DANCE SANADA DA DANCE
ハート燃やして不夜城
Burn your heart in the sleepless castle.
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA CHA RA CHA CHA CHA
断捨離命だぜ
It's all about letting go!
SANADA DA DANCE SANADA DA DANCE
心躍らせるために
To make your heart dance.
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA CHA RA CHA CHA CHANCE
熱く熱く火照ったなら
If you're feeling hot and fired up.
走れ回せ運命伸ばせ空に叫べ SANADANCE EXERCISE
Run and turn your fate, reach out and shout to the sky, SANADANCE EXERCISE.
Wow Wow Wow...
苦しい時やつらい時には体動かせよ SANADANCE
When times are tough or painful, move your body, SANADANCE.
天上天下唯我独尊
Throughout heaven and earth, I alone am the honored one.
みんなで踊ろうぜ SANADANCE Let's Go
Let's all dance, SANADANCE, let's go!
Take a Chance! Change the world!
深呼吸 Ba-Hoooooo!
Deep breath, Ba-Hoooooo!
本日も最終最後のお時間まで
Thank you very much for staying with us
兎田ぺこら6周年ライブにお付き合いいただきまして、
until the very end of the Usada Pekora
誠にありがとうございました。
6th Anniversary Live.
はい、ありがとうございました。ありがとうございました。
Yes, thank you very much. Thank you very much.
残念ではございますが、まもなく
Unfortunately, today's live will soon
本日のライブはすべて終了とさせていただきます。
come to a close.
メンバーシップカードをお持ちのお客様にご案内申し上げます。
We have an announcement for customers who have a membership card.
メンバーシップカードをお持ちの方は、このあとの
Those who have a membership card can also
22時15分より行われるアンコールライブにもご参加いただけます。
participate in the encore live starting at 22:15.
お持ちでない方もまだ間に合いますので、これを機にぜひご加入ください。
It's not too late for those who don't have one, so please join us.
また、グッズ販売のほうもまもなくカートオープンとなります。
Also, the merchandise cart will be opening soon.
22時10分より販売となりますので、ご購入をご検討の
Sales will start at 22:10, so please check the
皆様は、販売サイトにてご購入ください。
sales site if you're considering a purchase.
明日のご案内を申し上げます。
Here is the information for tomorrow.
明日の営業は通常通り夜から配信を行います。
Tomorrow's business will consist of a stream starting in the evening.
明日も兎田ぺこら、張り切ってまいりますので、ご来店お待ちしております。
Usada Pekora will be in high spirits tomorrow, we look forward to your visit.
大変名残惜しくはございますが、本日はこれにて
It is with great regret, but we will now
ライブ終了とさせていただきます。
conclude today's live.
最終最後までお付き合いいただきありがとうございました。
Thank you for staying with us until the very end.
周年3D LIVE ぺこらRUSH！！！！！！！ ぺこ！
Anniversary 3D Live: Pekora RUSH!!!!!!! Peko!